

Berlin/Germany

□ (+49) 1520 7961492 | ■ utku@turunc.me | 📅 utku.turunc.me | 🖫 utkuturunc |

Summary ₋

Software Engineer of two years with additional three years of experience in full-stack web development from freelance projects.

Professionally, I have been developing backends in Play Framework (Scala), Spring Boot (Kotlin) and Express/Koa (NodeJS). I have experience in developing and designing microservices and I also have experience in AWS, Google Cloud Platform, Docker and Kubernetes as I've been taking active responsibilities in DevOPS for several projects.

Spending two years at a software house enabled me to work on several different projects allowing me to get experienced with various technologies and every part of the software development cycle from design to deployment. I have been mainly focused on backend development but due to my freelance projects and personal interests, I am also highly fluent in ReactJS and it's ecosystem including React-Router, Redux and GraphQL.

My current technology of choice is Scala, namely Play Framework and Akka. I am actively trying to develop a more functional style of programming.

Work Experience

McMakler GmbH. Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Aug. 2018 - Present

- Working as a NodeJS backend developer for in house build CRM system.
- Developing and maintaining microservices.

Valensas Istanbul, Turkey

Jul. 2016 - Jul. 2018 SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Worked at artificial intelligence projects, focusing on chatbots.
- · Designed a chatbot framework that can manage conversation states, execute timed jobs, integrate with other web services, use machine learning and natural language processing in order to understand user input.
- · Worked mostly as a Backend Software Engineer, also developed Web UI using ReactJS for chatbot administration feature

Freelance Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Jan. 2013 - Jul. 2016 • Worked on several small to medium scale freelance projects as a full stack developer.

- Stack of choice is NodeJS (Koa) or Play Framework (Scala) + ReactJS with GraphQL.
- · Mostly took part on the backend and admin ui.
- · Completed a directory of blogs, truck rental and route planning app, motorcycle renting and tour reservation app, a donation app for a non-profit, a chat base party game.

Huawei Technologies Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Jul. 2015 - Sep. 2015

- Summer Internship at R&D department.
- · Worked on a data mining project using SpringMVC.
- Integrated Swagger into a project that is used for web service discovery.

Skills

Programming - Strong Scala, Typescript, JavaScript, NodeJS, Kotlin

Programming - Familiar Python, Spark, CoreNLP, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing

Web Development Play Framework, Akka, Spring Boot, ReactJS, Redux, GraphQL, Koa, HTML5, CSS, REST

DevOPS AWS, Google Cloud Engine, Docker, Kubernetes, Linux, Microservices

Database Redis, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Hibernate

Electronics SPICE, MagicVLSI, IRSIM, Matlab, Arduino, C, C++, Filter Design, VHDL, Analog Circuit Design, MEMS

Presentations

Turkey Artificial Intelligence Initiative (turkiye.ai)

Istanbul, Turkey

Presenter for Valensas Oct. 2017

• A talk about the usage of artificial intelligence in our projects

Education

ITÜ (Istanbul Technical University) (3.95/4)

Istanbul, Turkey

B.S. IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Sep. 2012 - Jun. 2013

• Transferred to Boğaziçi University at the end of the first year

Boğaziçi University (3.24/4)

Istanbul, Turkey

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING

Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2016

- Completed electronics specialization
- · Grade is not inclusive of first year

Projects

Immoforce Berlin, Germany

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - McMakler GmbH.

Aug. 2018 - Present

• Development and maintanence of microservices powering Immoforce, an internal CRM system for the company.

Undisclosed P2P Banking Application

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Feb. 2018 - Jul. 2018

- Developed several microservices for a modern peer to peer banking application
- Set up Kubernetes configurations and deployment pipelines.
- Responsible for core banking and social feeds.
- Project uses Spring Boot and Hibernate for core banking, Scala (Akka) for social feeds

Valensas VoT Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Jul. 2016 - Mar. 2018

- Valensas VoT is a complete customizable chatbot solution that includes conversation management, natural language processing in English and Turkish, machine learning and scheduled tasks.
- Designed and developed the framework for this project that was used in several other projects.

Akbank Assistant - Akbank Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Sep. 2017 - May. 2018

- · Developed a chatbot for Akbank which can be used to transfer money and pay invoices, one of the largest banks in Turkey.
- The project was written as microservices in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to Akbank datacenters on Linux.
- Project has been released with a TV commercial and printed press coverage.

Boti - Turkish Airlines Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Feb. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Developed a chatbot for Turkish Airlines, a star alliance member and flag carrier airline of Turkey.
- The bot can be used to buy tickets, select seats, check-in, query flight statuses and more.
- The project was written as 4 microservices in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to AWS.

Hepsichat - Hepsiburada Chatbot

Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

Nov. 2016 - Feb. 2017

Jul. 2016 - Dec. 2016

- $\bullet \ \ \, \text{Developed a customer support chatbot for the largest e-commerce platform in Turkey, Hepsiburada.}$
- The chatbot greets users, collects information and solves specific issues, if it cannot resolve the issue it redirects the users to human agents, saving time and resources.
- $\bullet \ \ \, \text{The project was written in TypeScript and Scala (Play Framework, Spark and CoreNLP) and deployed to AWS Lambda.}$

AskTim - Chatbot Istanbul, Turkey

SOFTWARE ENGINEER - VALENSAS

- Developed a Slack bot that is integrated with several analytics providers such as Mixpanel and Google Analytics.
- The bot is able to process natural language and produce visual reports combining data from different sources.
- The project was written in Scala using Play Framework and CoreNLP and deployed to AWS.